Guide to the Tree Top, Inc. Records 1938-2009
Washington State University Libraries Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections
- Series 4: History, 1938-2008
  - Subseries 4.2: Photographs
    - Ross Plant
      - Pasty Tavenner and Jose Fuentes. Ross Plant Dryer Operators (4 photos), 1998 February (Box 12, Folder 04.26.12)
      - Lois Jones, Ross Plant QA Lab, 1998 February (Box 12, Folder 04.26.13)
      - Greg Melroy, Ross Plant QA manager with pie on his face (2 photos), 1998 May (Box 12, Folder 04.26.14)
      - Kim Mertz, Ross Plant Lab Tech and Greg Melroy. Kim collected the most money for Walk America 1998, and won the right to pie her boss., 1998 May (Box 12, Folder 04.26.15)
      - Alan Fife, Tony Landis, Simon Valenzuela, Ted Hull, Mitch Hudson, Scott Swedburg, Anselmo Pena, Clint McMurray, Joey Valenzuela, Rick Valenzuela, Greg Melroy--Ross Plant Burners (4 photos), 1998 August (Box 12, Folder 04.26.16)
      - Gordon Boshears, Chris Hernandez, Mitch Hudson, Keith Matson, Shawn Kunsman--Mechanics, 2000 May (Box 12, Folder 04.26.17)
      - Oscar Chiqui, Craftsman (2 photos), 2002 November (Box 12, Folder 04.26.18)
      - Larry Schlenker, Gordon Boshears, Mervin Hammer, Wes Wildman, Ernie Davidson, Alan Fife, Mitch Hudson, Chris Hernandez, Shawn Kunsman. Group created custom drying line at Ross Plant, 2003 April (Box 12, Folder 04.26.19)
      - Larry Schlenker, Gordon Boshears, Mervin Hammer, Wes Wildman, Ernie Davidson, Mitch Hudson. Group created custom drying line at Ross Plant, 2003 April (Box 12, Folder 04.26.20)
      - Evaporated apples, Undated (Box 12, Folder 04.26.21)
      - Terry Morgan, Undated (Box 12, Folder 04.26.22)
      - Robotic Palletizer "Matilda" (23 photos), 2000 April (Box 12, Folder 04.26.23)
    - Other Tree Top Plants
      - Les Wright, Margaret Smart, Bill Albee, Marta Solis, Dennis Mettler, Dolores Chavez. Watermill (3 photos), 1999 July (Box 12, Folder 04.27.01)
      - Exterior, Compton Plant, California (2 photos), Circa 1990s (Box 12, Folder 04.27.02)
      - Sign for Sunnyside Plant, 1990s? (Box 12, Folder 04.27.03)
    - Unlabeled negatives
      - Photographs (collection of sleeved negatives, unlabeled, from binder), 1960-2000 (Box 14, Folder 04.28)
    - Slides (organized chronologically)
      - Glass bottles of apple juice in various stages of production, 1974 (Box 13)
      - Equipment in plant and apples on conveyor belt, 1975 September (Box 13)
      - Canned and bottled juice on production line, 1976 January (Box 13)
      - Stacking and constructing pallets, 1980 July (Box 13)
      - Employees in various poses (eating lunch, showing off paychecks, standing outside of facility, etc.), Undated (Box 13)
      - Apple trees, 1980 August (Box 13)
      - Empty apple bins, Undated (Box 13)
      - Constructing apple bins, Undated (Box 13)
      - Peeled apples and apple rings on production line, 1980 October (Box 13)
      - Award presentation, 1980 November (Box 13)
      - Loading pallets with boxes of juice, 1981 January (Box 13)
      - Constructing apple bins and pallets, Undated (Box 13)
      - Equipment, 1981 April (Box 13)
      - Cans on production line, Undated (Box 13)
      - Employees working on production line, Undated (Box 13)
      - Equipment, 1981 June (Box 13)
      - Close-up of forklift, 1981 July-August (Box 13)
      - Employee in safety gear, Undated (Box 13)
      - Aerial shots of plant, 1981 October-December (Box 13)
      - Warehouse full of Tree Top Boxes, Undated (Box 13)
      - Processing Equipment, 1983 June (Box 13)
      - Employees on production line, Undated (Box 13)
      - Bottle juice on production line, Undated (Box 13)
      - Laboratory equipment, Undated (Box 13)
      - Architectural model of new building, 1983 November (Box 13)
      - Quality control inspecting canned juice, 1984 July (Box 13)
      - Graphs indicating Tree Top's standing among apple juice manufacturers, projected growth, output of dried apple products, juice sales, equity, sales of single strength juices, sales of concentrated juices, sales of blended juices, 1985 (Box 13)
      - Color graphics illustrating topics such as taxes, retirement, economic impact, health benefits, payroll, employees, and schools, Undated (Box 13)
      - Slides with inspirational slogans such as "Ideas are useless unless used" and "Tools that eliminate risk, eliminate action.", Undated (Box 13)
      - Apples on production line, 1986-1988 (Box 13)
      - Apple peeling equipment, Undated (Box 13)
      - Apple bins, Undated (Box 13)
      - Cases of canned juice being prepared for shipment, Undated (Box 13)
      - Snapple products on production line, 1993 November (Box 13)
      - Tree Top Juice boxes on production line, Undated (Box 13)
      - Apple bins, Undated (Box 13)
    - Miscellaneous
      - Black and white slides of Wenatchee plant fire?, Undated (Box 13)
      - Woman looking into microscope, labeled "Kraft Consulting.", Undated (Box 13)
      - Woman in laboratory, Undated (Box 13)
      - Unidentified man, Undated (Box 13)
      - World Map, Undated (Box 13)
      - Aerial photos of Selah plant, Undated (Box 13)
    - Product Line
      - Juice Fizz, Undated (Box 13)
      - Del Monte Fruit Cups, Undated (Box 13)
      - Seneca canned juice, Undated (Box 13)
      - Just like Shortenin', Undated (Box 13)
      - Tree Top Sparkling Apple Juice, Undated (Box 13)
      - Natural Apple juice line, Undated (Box 13)
      - Grocery Store shelf display, Undated (Box 13)
      - Natural Apple Juice, Apple Juice, Pear-Apple, and Pear-Grape, Undated (Box 13)
      - Applesauce, Fruit Punch, and Fruit Blends, Undated (Box 13)
      - Apple Cinnamon Cheerios, Undated (Box 13)
      - Juice blends, Undated (Box 13)
      - Tree Top bottled juice, Undated (Box 13)
    - Production
      - Cases of juice in warehouse, Undated (Box 13)
      - Canned juice on production line, Undated (Box 13)
      - Peeled apples on production line, Undated (Box 13)
      - Glass bottles of juice from empty bottles to finished product, Undated (Box 13)
      - Miscellaneous equipment, Undated (Box 13)
      - Close-ups of workers on production line, Undated (Box 13)
    - Orchards
      - Woman picking apples, Undated (Box 13)
      - Distant and close-up pictures of apple trees and orchards, Undated (Box 13)
      - Orchards being sprayed, Undated (Box 13)
      - Vineyards, Undated (Box 13)
      - Man kneeling in orchard holding apples, Undated (Box 13)
    - Advertisements and Promotions
      - Woman's hand holding apple, Undated (Box 13)
      - Ad, "Four Refreshing Ways to Tree Top Your Day.", Undated (Box 13)
      - Ad, "The Great, Natural Apple Juice Taste Test.", Undated (Box 13)
      - The Pure and Natural Cookbook, Undated (Box 13)
      - Woman at table with family drinking juice, Undated (Box 13)
      - Woman pouring juice, Undated (Box 13)
      - Recipe booklet, "20 Ways to Drink an Apple.", Undated (Box 13)
      - Ad, "Taste Pure and Nothing But Juice," (three versions), Undated (Box 13)
      - Tree Top 1985 Calendar, 1985 (Box 13)
      - Drawing of wagon vendor selling Tree Top Juice, Undated (Box 13)
  - Subseries 4.3: Audiovisual and electronic media
    - Healthy Choices for Kids (corresponding handouts and programs located in Box #3). Video recording, VHS format, 1990s (Box 17)
    - Tree Top Logo and Artwork (compact disc), Undated (Box 17)
    - Tree Top Sprayfield Riparian Enhancement Project (compact disc), Undated (Box 17)
    - Selah Days (compact disc), 2003 (Box 17)
    - Gee Whiz: The Story of Grady Auvil. Video recording (DVD), 2008 (Box 17)
    - Minutes from corporate meetings (digital files on USB drive), 1960s-2000s (Box 17)
    - Oral history audiorecordings
      - Interview with Don Aliyea. Audio recording (microcassette), Circa 1980 (Box 17)
      - Interview with Ray Colbert (2 tapes). Audio recording (microcassette), Circa 1980 (Box 17)
      - Interview with Dennis Colleran. Audio recording (microcassette), Circa 1980 (Box 17)
      - Interview with Bob Dennis. Audio recording (microcassette), Circa 1980 (Box 17)
      - Interview with Ray Hager. Audio recording (microcassette), Circa 1980 (Box 17)
      - Interview with Russ Jones. Audio recording (microcassette), Circa 1980 (Box 17)
      - Interview with Joe Morin. Audio recording (microcassette), Circa 1980 (Box 17)
      - Interview with Norm Slowe and Inetta Workman. Audio recording (microcassette), Circa 1980 (Box 17)
      - Interview with Maury Westberg. Audio recording (microcassette), Circa 1980 (Box 17)
  - Subseries 4.4: Oversized materials
    - Goodfruit Grower (periodical), 2009 February (Box 18, Folder 04.31.01)
    - Tree Top--Important Processing Outlet, The Goodfruit Grower, 1967 December 1 (Box 18, Folder 04.31.02)
    - Advertisements, 1948 (Box 18, Folder 04.32.01-04.32.02)
    - Advertisements, 1947-1969 and Undated (Box 18, Folder 04.33.01-04.33.02)
    - Marketing packet: "9 Good Reasons Why You Should Stock Tree Top's New Pure Fruit Juices." Folder, recipes, and promotional brochure featuring Pear, Apple and Pear, and Grape juices, Circa 1970s (Box 18, Folder 04.34)
    - Annual meeting pamphlet, 1976 (Box 18, Folder 04.34)
    - Folder for Healthy Choices for Kids program, 1990s (Box 18, Folder 04.34)
    - Six original artist renderings of apple processing for 1996 annual report, 1996 (Box 18, Folder 04.34)
    - I am 100% Pure Tree Top bumper stickers (3 items), Mid-1980s (Box 18, Folder 04.35)
    - Group Photo: Board of Directors, Undated (Box 18, Folder 04.36)
    - Color photographs (mounted) and ephemera
      - Corporate headquarters, Selah, 1970s (Box 18, Folder 04.37)
      - Cashmere Plant, 1970s (Box 18, Folder 04.38)
      - Wenatchee Plant, 1970s (Box 18, Folder 04.39)
      - Selah Plant, 1970s (Box 18, Folder 04.4)
      - Ross Packing Company Calendar, 1938 (Box 21)
      - Tree Top Monthly Planner, 2009 (Box 21)
      - Mission and Vision Statements Poster, 2000s (Box 21)
      - Values Poster, 2000s (Box 21)
    - Newspapers (includes some reproductions)
      - Apple Processing in Valley enjoys boom year, Yakima Herald, 1957 December 8 (Box 21)
      - 'Cider' from d'Anjous? Wenatchee World, 1972 May 8 (Box 21)
      - Tree Top Celebrates New Plant With Open House March 27, Selah Valley Optimist, 1974 March 21 (Box 21)
      - Another First for Tree Top, Los Angeles Times, 1975 July 28 (Box 21)
      - Tree Top Offers Two New Juices, The IMP, 1975 July-August (Box 21)
      - Charbonneau obituary, The Goodfruit Grower, 1978 May 1 (Box 21)
      - Tree Top makes water, but it won't quench city, Cashmere Valley Record, 1994 April 27 (Box 21)
      - Agriculture is where private jobs are, Yakima Herald, 1995 February 11 (Box 21)
      - Tree Top hard-pressed to find new juice markets, Seattle Post-Intelligencer, 1995 October 2 (Box 21)
      - Can Tree Top squeeze out the competition with its new three--apple blend? Yakima Herald Republic, 1996 May 17 (Box 21)
      - Tree Top plans to run former Seneca plant to capacity, Prosser Record Bulletin, 1999 February 3 (Box 21)
      - Tri-Cities Herald, announcement of Tom Stokes as new president, 1999 April 8 (Box 21)
      - Tree Top closes Watermill purchase, East Oregonian, 1999 May 8 (Box 21)
      - Watermill sale to Tree Top is final, Walla Walla Union-Bulletin, 1999 May 7 (Box 21)
      - Here's a Chance to Speak up for the Valley's Quiet Heroes, Yakima Herald Republic. Interview with Pat Moss, 2002 March 10 (Box 21)
      - Beyond the Core: Tree Top stays in the game by creating new products that include more than just apples, Yakima Herald Republic, 2002 December 1 (Box 21)
      - Tree Top is branching out into some new food lines, Yakima Business Times, 2003 November 14 (Box 21)
- Series 5: Artifacts
  - Tree Top shipping carton (cardboard), 1950s (Box 19)
  - Charbonneau Tree Top Cider jug, 1950s (Box 19)
  - Tree Top paper caps, Undated (Box 19)
  - Tree Top can openers (2 items), Undated (Box 19)
  - Tree Top key chain, Undated (Box 19)
  - Tree Top button, "Tree Top Your Day!", Undated (Box 19)
  - Tree Top button, "Tree Top We Always Give You 100 percent.", Undated (Box 19)
  - Tree Top patches (2 items), Undated (Box 19)
  - Tree Top can openers (2 items), Undated (Box 19)
  - Green Tree Top binders (3 items), Undated (Box 20)
  - White Tree Top binder, Undated (Box 20)